{"Topic": "Rivers and Tributaries", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Questions : Rivers - Origins and Tributaries.", "op1": "Gomati", "op2": "Betwa", "op3": "Ghaghra", "op4": "Gandak", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a tributary of the River Ganga?", "op1": "Ravi", "op2": "Sutlej", "op3": "Beas", "op4": "Jhelum", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers has its origin in the Rohtang Pass, Himachal Pradesh?", "op1": "River Kaveri", "op2": "River Godavari", "op3": "River Periyar", "op4": "River Krishna", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Tungabhadra, a river formed by the confluence of Tunga and Bhadra rivers is the chief tributary of -", "op1": "Godavari", "op2": "Krishna", "op3": "Kaveri", "op4": "Tapti", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers originates at the hill station Mahabaleswar in Maharashtra?", "op1": "Mahanadi", "op2": "Narmada", "op3": "Tapti", "op4": "Chambal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers originates in Chhattisgarh?", "op1": "Tungabhadra", "op2": "Godavari", "op3": "Kaveri", "op4": "Krishna", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Hemavathi, Simsha and Arkavati are the tributaries of which of the following rivers?", "op1": "Chambal", "op2": "Sabarmathi", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Tapti", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers has its origin in the Aravalli hills in Rajasthan?", "op1": "Amarkantak", "op2": "Mahabaleswar", "op3": "Betul", "op4": "Nasik", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "From which of the following places does the River Narmada originate?", "op1": "Pennar", "op2": "Kaveri", "op3": "Krishna", "op4": "Tunga", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers originates from Brahmagiri Hills in Karnataka?", "op1": "Ravi", "op2": "Yamuna", "op3": "Indus", "op4": "Jhelum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Sutlej, Dras and Zanskar are the tributaries of -", "op1": "Ganga", "op2": "Chenab", "op3": "Yamuna", "op4": "Jhelum", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is popular name of the river formed by the confluence of Chandra and Bhagha rivers?", "op1": "Tons", "op2": "Kosi", "op3": "Ken", "op4": "Hindon", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a tributary of river Yamuna?", "op1": "Padma", "op2": "Meghna", "op3": "Subansiri", "op4": "Brahmaputra"}, {"Question": "Which of the following rivers is not a tributary of the River Godavari?", "op1": "Bhima", "op2": "Manjira", "op3": "Bindusara", "op4": "Penganga", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The place of confluence of the rivers Alaknanda and Bhagirathi is known as", "op1": "Rudraprayag", "op2": "Devaprayag", "op3": "Haridwar", "op4": "Kedarnath", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one of the following pairs is correctly matched?", "op1": "Damodar", "op2": "Mahanadi", "op3": "Narmada", "op4": "Tapti", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following rivers originates at Amarkantak?", "op1": "Rajasthan State", "op2": "Gujarat State", "op3": "Chhotanagpur Plateau", "op4": "Arunachal Pradesh hills", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The river Damodar rises in the", "op1": "Bhind", "op2": "Ratlam", "op3": "Mhow", "op4": "Ujjain", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Where does Chambal river originate from?", "op1": "Indus", "op2": "Ganga", "op3": "Sutlej", "op4": "Brahmaputra", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following Indian rivers does not have its source in Tibet?", "op1": "Ghaghara", "op2": "Gomti", "op3": "Kosi", "op4": "Yamuna", "Answer": 1}]}